

CONTACT



Bengaluru, India 560048



9567699411



aravindmj97@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced software developer with 4 years of experience. Started as a scholar at SAP and completed an M.Tech from BITS Pilani. Skilled in ABAP, ABAP OO, JavaScript, SAP UI5, SAP Fiori elements, SAP RAP, SAP BOPF, CDS, and MySQL. Equipped with a strong academic background and diverse skill set to contribute to software development projects.

SKILLS

- ABAP
- ABAP-OO
- JavaScript
- Java
- SAPUI5
- SAP Fiori
- RAP
- BOPF
- OData

ARAVIND MJ



EXPERIENCE

Developer SAP Labs India - Bengaluru 04/2023 - Current

- Design and development of Key Features and Apps for PLM Discrete BOM (S/4HANA Cloud and OP)
- Architected and developed an application for the Maintenance of BOM Variants in Matrix
- Identity & Access Management (IAM) Contact for the PLM Discrete BOM.
- Mentoring team members enabling them to develop good-quality applications.

Associate Developer SAP Labs India - Bengaluru 01/2021 - 04/2023

- Design and development of Manage Multilevel BOM Maintenance app for maintenance of BOM explosion structure. -ODataV2-based SAP Fiori SmartTemplate application with extensive custom implementations via extensions for enabling hierarchical maintenance of BOMs using JSON-bound SAPUI5 TreeTable with SmartControls embedded.
- Development of BOM Item Grouping for logical grouping of BOM Components in the Manage Multilevel BOM Maintenance app -Integration of RAP-based BOM Item Grouping BO to enable logical grouping capability in the SAPUI5 TreeTable.
- Development of BOM Mass Maintenance Applications with asynchronous execution modes using OData V4 BOM APIs, BOM PaaS APIs and SAP Fiori Elements.
- Design and development of PoC for enhancing customer experience in S/4HANA Cloud and SAP BTP - Worked with ABAP Reports for running business logic in regular time intervals and for firing notifications using the Notification Provider Interface.
- Feature Enhancement of ABAP RESTful Application Programming Model (RAP) based BOM APIs.
- Developed PoC for the Integration of SAP EPD Collaboration in SAP BTP with Maintain Bill Of Material in S/4HANA.
- Design and development of PoC for BOM Comparison app using SAP Fiori Elements and RAP based ODataV2 Service.

Scholar@SAP SAP Labs India - Bengaluru, India 08/2019 - 01/2021

- Design and development of SAPUI5 application for internal SAP Conversational Al-based ChatBot configuration.
- Integration and development of SAP BTP Document Information

- MySQL
- MS Power Automate

LANGUAGES

Malayalam: First Language

English:

Proficient

Extraction in team project as part of SAP Innovision for Scholars.

Flutter Developer Intern Zartek Technologies Pvt Ltd - Ernakulam 05/2019 - 07/2019

- Development of UI for a Crypto Currency Wallet application
- Integration of a Chat Kit to a Learning Application



C2

EDUCATION

MTech: Software Engineering
Birla Institute of Technology and Science - Pilani, 07/2021
GPA: 7.54

BTech: Computer Science and Engineering Cochin University of Science and – Kochi, 06/2019 GPA: 8.75



ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Finalists in SAP PLM Discrete Innovation Challenge - Maintenance of BOM Variants in Matrix

(10/2022 - 01/2023)

Design and development of SAP CAP based application using SAP Product Structure service running on SAP BTP



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Scriptor (01/2019 - 10/2021)

- A minimalistic notes app
- Published on Google Play Store

Hand Gesture-based On-Screen Smart Board (06/2021 - 08/2021)

- Available on Github
- Developed using Google MediaPipe



HOBBIES

- Drums
- Music
- Photography and Videography
- Badminton